All right, so let's I guess should we
knock something off and then do some do
some of the leftover questions? I mean
>> Absolutely.
>> We can start with Israel. I mean
>> Yeah, let's do that. This is sickening.
So the Israeli Knesset, as you pointed
out, has passed this law calling for
the death penalty by hanging but only
for Palestinians who are convicted of
taking a life during the commission of a
terrorist act. But of course, it's the
extreme right-wing government in Israel
that decides what meets the criteria of
a terrorist attack and what doesn't.
>> And this would by definition not apply
to
West Bank settlers who attack who are
terrorists who are terrorizing and
attacking
you know Palestinians who are locals in
order to you know just to get rid of
ethnically cleanse them and in many
cases to steal their land.
>> Yeah.
>> And and so yeah, I mean basically
their their celeb Ben-Gvir was
photographed or videotaped
toasting this passage of this law with
champagne. He said this is a quote, "We
will count them the hang the hanged
Palestinians one by one." He said while
laughing.
>> Yeah.
>> This is a bloodthirsty government. John,
at this point nobody can question that
it's an apartheid state cuz this is I
mean even apartheid South Africa didn't
have a separate legal code for whites
and blacks.
>> that's exactly right.
>> an egalitarian society. It was just in
practice it was they had apartheid.
In this case, this is
they're they're codifying
racial and and and discrimination within
the areas in their control. And I know
what they're going to say is well, this
applies not to Israel proper, it applies
to the West Bank. But that's sophistry.
They've controlled this territory since
as long as you and I are alive.
>> And it specifically
it specifically exempts
settlers who kill Palestinians
from coverage.
So, if you're a settler, you're just
some guy from New Jersey who who goes to
the West Bank,
opens fire on some Palestinian family,
you're good to go.
But, if you're a Palestinian who shoots
the guy from New Jersey to protect your
home from being seized by these American
settlers,
you're hanged.
It's a nice country.
>> Yeah, nice country. So, the death
penalty was abolished in 1954.
>> Yeah.
>> The only exception was Adolf Eichmann,
who was hanged in 1962.
And so, basically, I don't know how they
justified that just by saying, "Well,
war crimes are different." or whatever.
Because if there's no death penalty, I
don't know, maybe they he was tried not
under Israeli criminal law, right? I
So,
so basically, this is a country that's
kind of there's been a small L attempt
they said there's been a strong
tradition of small L liberalism.
The you know, the whole kibbutz movement
was a socialist movement. I mean,
there's no left at all. There's no
moderate at all. This is a far, far
right John, how is any How is anyone
going to still in the United States How
are the Zionists going to be able to
continue to defend Israel? I mean, I
know they'll try, but how are they going
to do it?
>> They they they will. They'll try.
Um
but it's going to it's going to be one
of those disingenuous things, Ted. How
can you possibly defend something like
this?
>> It's disgusting.
>> Can you imagine?
>> Equal justice under the law is
absolutely How can you claim that you're
a democracy if the only democracy in the
Middle East if you don't have equal
justice under the law?
>> That's right.
That's right. No, this this There
There's just no upside to this. There's
no way to defend it. There's just no
way.
>> I mean, do you think what what do you
think is going to happen when they start
hanging Palestinians, which they will?
And by the way, this is a mandatory
sentence, John. I mean, like if you're
found guilty of this offense,
they're supposed to hang you within 90
days. There's a few provisions for a
slight delay, but probably not to be
granted in most cases. No clemency is
possible, right? So later also, if it
turns out that the person's not guilty,
got to do the scare quotes for that.
Well, there's no there's no take-backs.
It's not
No.
>> um
>> When you're dead, you're dead. That's
the end of it.
>> So how how on earth are the same people
who criticize Iran for hanging political
dissidents?
Uh how are they going to be able to
criticize defend the Israelis? I mean,
it's the same thing.
>> I can actually easily see how some of
these um
some of these well, two camps. First of
all, right-wingers on Capitol Hill.
You know, they they view the death
penalty as legit punishment and that
it's better
Let me rephrase. It's less bad to kill
an innocent person than to allow a
um
a guilty person to live, okay?
>> exactly the other way around.
>> Exactly the other way. I'm I'm with you.
Uh that's the one hand. On the other
hand, among Democrats, I think that the
the the most ardent Zionists among the
Democrats are going to say, "Well, you
know,
terrorism,
we don't want another 9/11. We don't
want another October 7th."
>> Or they'll just be like, "La la la la
la. I can't hear you." They just won't
comment on it.
>> Sure. Sickening.
Absolutely sickening.
>> Um James Kelly, thanks for the five. Uh
do you think the new law is because
they're losing power, kind of like how
the Nazis fast-tracked mass killing
before they were
overthrown.
>> That's a good point.
I hadn't considered that.
>> I think it's part of it. I think it's
also like when a country is spinning is
going down the toilet and they just stop
caring what everyone else thinks. Um you
know, that's they're so isolated. They
have their heads so far up their own
asses and they think like we're all
alone. We can't count on anyone. We have
to do things our way. It's It's the
logic of radicalization.
>> Mhm.
>> I I think it's a
huge mistake for from a Zionist point of
view. You know, you
The Zionists' biggest problem is that
they're perceived as being main like
cruel maniacs. This isn't going to help.
>> I have to agree.
No, this is just going to piss people
off.
>> Want to support the show with style? Go
to deeprogram.live and check out our
merch. That's deeprogram.live
or check out the description below.
Thanks for watching.